<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>NRE-Bytes</title>
    <link>https://mayuresh82.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on NRE-Bytes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 15:05:46 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mayuresh82.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>BGP based Anycast as a Service</title>
      <link>https://mayuresh82.github.io/2020/11/28/automatic_service_discovery_anycast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 15:05:46 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mayuresh82.github.io/2020/11/28/automatic_service_discovery_anycast/</guid>
      <description>Orchestration and Service Discovery The term orchestration, in part, refers to the automated deployment of services or applications inside of your infrastructure. The orchestration solution takes care of things like resource allocation, entitlements and the placement of an application or a service on a machine or a group of machines. If the machine your service is deployed on fails for some reason, the orchestration system automatically detects the failure and re-deploys the service according to the service policy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with Network Automation</title>
      <link>https://mayuresh82.github.io/2019/05/06/getting_started/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 15:05:46 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mayuresh82.github.io/2019/05/06/getting_started/</guid>
      <description>Getting Started with Network Automation Network Automation is the “art” of automating repetitive tasks related to network provisioning, deployment, monitoring and alerting. The reason its an art is because you can conceptualize and develop very creative methods to achieve your network automation goals. To get started, it is important to first identify a problem that needs to be solved, ideally a simple one. This helps establish clear goals and helps navigate the myriad web of libraries and open source tools available at your disposal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mayuresh82.github.io/search/placeholder/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mayuresh82.github.io/search/placeholder/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mayuresh82.github.io/top/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mayuresh82.github.io/top/about/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my blog, where I try and share real world tips and techniques covering practical aspects of network automation, monitoring, configuration management and other infrastructure related problems. I am a Network Engineer turned Network Automation guy / Network Reliability Engineer who loves building micro-service based frameworks for the monitoring, provisioning and deployment of large/web scale network environments. I am a fan of Open Source but less so than building things myself to get the job done :) I prefer coding in Golang and Python and recently have developed an active interest in front end development using React-JS.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>